[Music]
welcome my name is BU Koto and my name
is Monica alja and together we work at
Microsoft engineering team that develops
business Central here in Copenhagen
Denmark
today in this session we'll talk about
improvements in our integration with
Power Platform business Central is well
connected with Power Platform already
and we will talk about power automate
new features that we uh delivered this
wave we'll talk about power pages and
few other areas as
well several tools uh are part of Power
Platform starting with co-pilot studio
power apps power automate powerbi power
pages and several uh supporting
Technologies data verse AI Builder and
connectors connectors are very important
because those allow you to connect to
different
systems yes exactly and we have more
than thousand connectors built in
already and of course those include the
business Central connectors as well
we'll start with our integration with
power automate and the improvements that
we made in that area business Central is
already uh well or nicely connected with
power automate it allows you to build
automations and and and different
workflows uh in different categories
approval flows automated flows and and
even custom actions based on power
automate and we have a nice um single
entry point single UI to start building
flows uh with power automate starting
from with within business Central you
can work on approval uh workflows uh so
you think about a scenario where you
approve documents using teams or Outlook
uh you can work on automated flows that
run in the background for instance
process processing some emails
processing uh invoices coming from
different third- party systems and you
can think about building an action that
is based on a flow for instance sending
an an update to a customer using email
or or some other means that's right and
from this wave onwards we don't need
feature management this is the default
view that we will get so the single
entry point will always be available
yes and whatever you choose uh whichever
option you choose you will end up uh
looking at different templates and the
templates that we have in our our
catalog and in in that Spirit we have
improved plenty of of areas in in our
experience in our templates and the
first thing that you will notice is that
we have right now improved the approval
uh workflows uh and that means we have
right now added an ability for power
automate to Access Data from business
Central for approvers and pull it into
the flow uh you will see that in a demo
in a moment we have also improved the
workflows and the templates uh based on
environment and Company so this is right
now sent from business Central to power
automate and I think the best way is to
see it in a demo yes so let's see what
improvements we have made with approval
templates so let's assume the scenario
where we want to do an approval setup
for sales orders so let's just go ahead
to the sales order card
page and here under the automate menu we
can see the single entry point that BL
just mentioned and this will be the
default behavior all of these will open
the gallery of templates under the
appropriate category so let's just go
ahead and create the approval
flow and now we can see a list of
templates that are available for sales
order approval I'll just go ahead and
select one of them and you can see that
it is figuring out all the connections
that are needed for this
flow and here are the new improvements
that we have made in this wave so as you
can see this is only asking for
approvals title and not the environment
and the company or for that matter even
the approve who the approver is how is
that possible because from this wave we
are actually sending all this
information information from business
Central already so we are defaulting
these parameters depending on where you
are running the setup from so in this
case the environment will be sandbox for
for example and cronis Company and the
approval will be honored from approval
user setup table so let me just go ahead
and create this flow and add an
appropriate
title so now the flow is created so we
are now in power automate and we can see
the flow that we just created and as you
can see this is the same flow that you
might have seen in previous releases but
now we have made some improvements for
example we have added this new action
called get approver which is the action
that is responsible to dynamically fetch
the approver of the requester of the
approval request how do we get this
information we get this information from
approval user setup table so let's just
see how the setup table looks
like and and this is how the setup looks
like so for example in case of Megan
gradia is the approver and so on so this
table will be honored by the action that
we just have introduced in the approval
template and these are the new changes
no more parameters and approval is also
fetched from BC super can we see that in
action then yes but after we introduce
AI in the flow super let's uh switch
back to the presentation then and talk
about Ai and in this wave we added added
a little bit of that logic into our
approval templates and you will see that
in a moment in a demo uh but what is
important is to mention that AI Builder
uh is one of the components in Power
Platform that incl introduced special
actions that includes GPT logic you can
use those actions to build any flow uh
of your choice but we have used them all
for templates uh related to business
Central and to to business scenarios we
will be adding later in this wave
several templates starting from the ones
that you that you see on screen that
include GPT logic and the interesting
one is actually something that um
enhances the approval approval of s
sales orders where uh Azure open AI GPT
action can summarize the sales ORD so
let's see that in action so in this demo
you're going to see a new template that
we have introduced that uses the GPT
action so let's just see how it looks
like so under the approval flow we can
see that there is a new GPT action uh
template and for the sake of time I have
just followed the steps and created a
flow already so let's see how the flow
looks like so this is the flow that uses
the GPT action and it's similar to the
approval flow that we have seen before
but now it also introduces a new action
here uh that creates the summary for the
sales order details using GPT using a
prompt so what it does behind the scenes
it actually takes the sales order header
and sales order lines and creates a
summary that helps approver decide the
approval status for the request that is
being made let's see this in action for
this to work I would like to request BL
to act as Megan and send an approval
request okay so here I'm acting as Megan
I'm on the list of sales orders opening
the second one and I you can see that
the sales orderer has a couple of lines
here and uh uh request approval action
so I'm using the request approval action
to request approval from my from my
admin I'm the approver for Megan as per
the approval user setup and I have been
working in teams now so I got a
notification that Megan has sent me a
request let's see how the request looks
like so I can see that the request is
for the sales order and then there is a
very nice summary generated by GPT
action that tells me all the details
that I need to know about the sales
order before making the decision to
approve or reject this request it tells
me not only the order number but who who
the customer has been where is the
address of that customer what were the
lines what was the price of each of the
line and so on and that to in simple
easy to understand natural language so I
understand this is the valid request and
I'll just go ahead and approve it and
that's how simple it was thank you
Monica so as you have seen in this
amazing demo we are giving you
additional templates using GPT
technology it will be later in the wave
at the moment you're listening to this
recording or viewing this this video you
might see those actions or those those
templates already in your uh business
Central template Gallery but there will
be more of those coming later uh in the
wave and what is important about power
automated templates is that you can edit
the flow that is created uh as as a
output of that template you can add a
little bit different logic according to
to your requests you can also change the
uh The Prompt for instance that is used
in this GPT action if you want to do a
different summary of of the sales order
as an example and so on and so on this
is really really powerful and and and
opens uh additional possibilities for
you uh to extend business Central with
with GPT all right let's talk about uh
additional improvement in our connector
this is a new action uh we have a new
action in the connector which is called
find one record and uh it might be a bit
confusing but currently we already have
a an action that is called find records
uh that action is already available and
very popular it's very powerful um but
it has um it has some challenges so
first of all you need to understand the
o data query syntax not everyone is is
so familiar with with this how to find
specific data and it also returns always
a collection of Records even if only one
record is what you requested this is a
bit problematic if you're building more
complicated flows using power automate
so let's make your life easier we are
introducing a new action that allows you
to find just one record uh with a
friendly user interface friendly
settings and that record is retrieve
together um in one go so imagine a very
simple scenario where we would like to
build an action in business Central that
sends um a sales order a latest sales
order of a given customer to your
colleagues via teams and of course you
can build it right now using power
automate actions uh in our connector but
with this new find one record it is much
simple isn't it Monica yes let's see how
simple it is in demo so here we have the
flow to send the latest sales order for
a given customer and it's a very simple
flow because now we have added a new
action called fine one record as blasa
just explained and this action actually
allows to find the latest sales order
given on the customer number that we
have
selected you can add multiple new
conditions if needed and you can also
select which order to use for a given
field so you can say it's either
ascending or descending for for example
uh post code and so on and this was the
new action let's see it in
running so we are in the customers list
now and we have the action to send the
latest sales order which is promoted so
let's just go ahead and use this send
the latest sales order for adim
customer and what this will do is
actually it will allow me the option to
run the flow behind this action so now
that I've have clicked run flow I'm
expecting that it will find the last
sales order for adum and send the
Adaptive card for it on teams let's see
how it looks in
teams so here in teams I can see that
the card has been sent for the last
sales order for adopting Corporation
that's how simple it was to create the
flow with this new action let's talk
about a few other updates in our
connector we have made some additional
improvements as always we have added a
way to default the API route in our
actions making it even easier for you to
create uh flows we have updated some
tool tips we have made the triggers
available in the new Power automate
designer as you have seen in some of the
demos uh and one other change that we
want to talk about is that we have
hidden the V2 actions the old actions
that were available in our connector
before uh and that uh is important for
all of you who might still be using
those V2 actions in your flows your
flows will continue to run is that
correct Monica yes PL the existing flows
that use the V2 actions will continue to
run but we have of course a plan to
deprecate V2 actions fully in in the
next uh in the next year so please uh
edit your flows and change them to the
current set of actions which are V3
actions yes and it's very important to
note that this has nothing to do with V2
apis this is only about V2 actions in
the connector we are not deprecating V2
apis this is a very good point Monica so
maybe we should talk about the
difference a little bit of history and
what those V2 and V3 actions are in our
connector so V2 actions as you can see
the old V2 actions that are currently
hidden they used only the old apis the
V1 apis from business Central they were
limited to set of apis provided by
Microsoft only the current V3 actions
the actions that are currently uh the
only ones the only choice for you
actually uh when you're creating flows
are very flexible uh you have this new
field API category where you can choose
the category and of course you have apis
coming from Microsoft the standard V2
apis as Monica said v2.0 apis actually
uh but but you have also custom apis
various apis coming from Microsoft from
partners and so on uh and as well on top
of that also the end points that are
needed for workflows so plenty of of
options to choose from and this is the
future this is what you should be using
going forward yes in fact we have plans
of deprecating v1.0 apis okay that is
even uh better in terms of messaging you
guys need to switch to V3 actions and
start using the new apis and start
moving
forward let's talk about few other
things that we have uh worked on in this
wave we have actually for power ups a
new sample for uh allowing you to build
a scenario I have actually this app
loaded on my device here this is a
sample app that you can take from GitHub
and show uh to your customers it's a
different way of selling a scenario
where you are selling coffee machines
using mixed reality where you can
measure space and so on you might have
seen the demo of this app uh that we uh
that we did on one of our conferences
last year and this this sample is right
now available for you to
download we also are working right now
on linking data verse environments to
business Central environment this new
feature is already available in business
Central admin Center and you probably
have seen it in our release plans it
allows you to select one of the data
vers environment uh as a designated one
and linked and we already are uh using
that or honoring that also in our power
automate setup yes if the power automate
environment that you have linked to
business Central is not the default one
we actually use that one as the default
when the user has not done the power
automate environment setup in business
Central we also show this in for example
data verse assisted setup and it will be
also seen whether it's a link or not in
the power automate assisted
setup thanks Monica another area that we
need to talk about is power pages and
our integration with power Pages my
colleague sand vinaro has another
session in this event when he is
explaining all the new stuff that we
have delivered in this uh integration
currently in this wave so I would very
much encourage you to tune in to that
recording let's talk about one more
important feature in our uh integration
that is copilot in power automate we are
making your life life of creators even
easier where you can use natural
language to create Automation and that
feature is coming as preview later in
this wave we have a separate recording
in this event where we talk a little bit
more in detail about this particular
feature so please tune into that one uh
when you're
interested we also would like to talk
about our integration with co-pilot
Studio One of the tools from Power
Platform family allowing you to build
co-pilots or Bots and that is already
integrated with business Central through
our connector through Power automate
actions and also through plugins that
are available in copilot Studio we will
be covering more about copilot studio
and our integration uh in the coming
events uh so please tune in to more news
about our integration with copilot
Studio and I think at the end of this uh
recording we need to mention that there
are a couple of additional sessions
worth uh to watch as I mentioned the um
session about power automate and
co-pilot which uh uh which we recorded
together there is also a session that
talks about integration with data verse
that my colleagues recorded and that
mentions the virtual tables technology
also very important for Power Platform
uh for Power Platform integration there
is also a session uh from keny that
talks about updates in our documentation
and that also mentions uh integration
with Power Platform worth worth checking
out of course and as always all the
general uh business Central resources
are available at aka.ms slbc all uh all
the other links that you see on screen
and nothing has changed there please go
to ideas to submit new ideas talk to us
uh using Yammer or tune in to one of our
open uh office hours uh meetings that we
organize every couple of months for
Power Platform specifically and I think
that will be it from this uh session
thank you very much thank you very
much